《絕命律師》前情提要
Previously on "Better Call Saul."
為什么非要來這
Why'd we have to come here?
因為制作水準要高  要表演
Production value. Showmanship.
你準備簽了嗎  來簽吧
You ready to sign? Let's do this.
-梅薩維德銀行跑了  -怎么回事
- I lost Mesa Verde. - What happened?
他們繼續和哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所合作
Sticking with HHM.
凱文改變想法了
Kevin got his head turned.
-霍華德說服的嗎  -不  是查克
- By Howard? ‭- No, Chuck.
你真是太棒了  真...
You were fantastic truly...
我需要美工刀  尺子
I need an X-Acto knife, a ruler,
還有最好的復印機
and point me to your best copier.
這是在干什么
What's all this?
我要給外面的杜鵑花做個滴灌管
I needed a soaker for the rhododendrons out back.
停車場
冰爽禮物
*你的美臀真漂亮*
*Que lindo es tu cucu cucu*
*真的好漂亮*
*Tan bello tu cucu cucu*
*圓潤又松軟*
*Redondito y suavecito cucu*
*你的美臀真漂亮*
*Que lindo es tu cucu cucu*
*穿上緊身褲*
*Cuando te pones pantalón cucu*
*自摸你翹臀*
*Y te tocas por de--*
*別對我的美臀亂來*
*No te metas con mi cucu cucu*
*我知道你有嬌妻*
*Yo se que tienes tu mujer*
*別對我的美臀亂來*
*No te metas con mi cucu cucu*
*小伙子都目不轉睛*
*Nunca faltan los mirones cucu*
*就像你和別人那樣*
*Como tú y los demas cucu*
*你想看就看吧*
*Si quieres puedes mirar cucu*
*想看就看個夠*
*No que a ti te de la gana cucu*
*亂來賞你一耳光*
*Te daré una cachetada cucu*
*別*
*No --*
*美臀*
*...cucu cucu*
*我知道你有嬌妻*
*Yo se que tienes tu mujer**Cucu*
*美臀*
*Cucu*
絕命律師
第二季 第九集
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
翻譯  TheWalkingNerd  喵球球  肉松  克里斯
翻譯  joy_bwl  酸奶  西陵折枝  自然卷
校對  喃喃
時間軸   姜姜  夢龍
好了  一切準備就緒
Okay. All set.
后期  深山小新    總監  喃喃
打開微信   掃描左側二維碼
或搜索公眾號:    美劇炸了
了解最新影視資訊字幕信息
久等了
Thank you for your patience.
你不是說聽證會只是走形式而已嗎
Didn't you say that the hearing is more or less a formality?
實際工作已經完成了  對
Well, the real work's already been done, yes.
那樣的話  我自己應付得來
In that case, ‭I'm fine covering it myself.
凱文和佩奇不需要我們都去
Kevin and Paige ‭don't need both of us there.
你說得也許很對
That may be strictly true,
但我們想傳達正確的信息  是不是
but we want to send the right message, don't we?
我就是擔心你不舒服
I'm just worried about your comfort.
慶祝勝利最能讓我舒服
I find victory laps very comforting.
干得好  朋友
Well-done, my friend.
早上好
Good morning.
現在召開新墨西哥州銀監局會議
This meeting of the New Mexico State Banking Board is now in session.
今天來的是梅薩維德銀行
We have Mesa Verde here with us today,
他們由查爾斯·麥吉爾代表
and they're represented by Charles McGill.
真高興你回來  查爾斯
Nice to have you back, Charles.
謝謝  能回來真好
Thank you. Good to be back.
我和我的同事霍華德·哈姆林一起
I'm here with my colleague, Howard Hamlin.
我有幸向你們介紹凱文·沃弛泰爾先生
And may I introduce Mr. Kevin Wachtell,
梅薩維德集團總裁兼董事長
President and Chairman of Mesa Verde Holdings,
以及佩奇·諾維克女士
and Ms. Paige Novick,
梅薩維德高級法律顧問
Mesa Verde Senior Counsel.
歡迎你們
Hello and welcome.
工作人員認為
I believe staff has found the application
申請書基本符合通過標準
to meet the basic requirements for approval.
對不對
That's right, isn't it?
如果您允許的話
With your permission,
沃弛泰爾先生想做個簡要介紹
Mr. Wachtell would like to make a brief statement
以支持其申請
in support of the application.
專員先生
Mr. Commissioner,
新墨西哥州銀監局的女士們先生們
ladies and gentlemen of the New Mexico Banking Board,
我有幸能在今早坐在各位面前
I'm honored and grateful to appear before you this morning.
我們認為  我們提出的擴張
We believe ‭that our proposed expansion
符合亞利桑那州和我州的公眾利益
is in the public interest both for Arizona and our own state.
四十六年來  梅薩維德銀行信托的員工
For 46 years, the men and women of Mesa Verde Bank and Trust
為我們首屈一指的個性化服務和
have prided ourselves on personal service
對細節的執著感到驕傲
and attention to detail second to none.
梅薩維德經營的一級杠桿比率
Mesa Verde continues to operate at a Tier One leverage ratio
保持在11.2%  我們
of 11.2%, and we feel --
等下
Uh, hold on.
抱歉  沃弛泰爾先生  稍等一下
Excuse me, Mr. Wachtell. Just one moment.
怎么了
What's going on?
問一下吧
Well, let's find out.
專員先生  有什么需要我們解釋的嗎
Uh, Mr. Commissioner, is there something we can clarify?
有
Uh, yes.
能告訴我們擬設的
Can you give us the address
斯科茨代爾支行的地址嗎
of the proposed Scottsdale branch again?
當然可以
Certainly.
亞利桑那州斯科茨代爾
It's 1216 Rosella Drive,
羅塞拉路1216號  85262
Scottsdale, Arizona, 85262.
1-2-1-6?
好  我現在看著的申請書
Okay. Because the application I'm looking at today
清清楚楚地寫著1216號
clearly gives the address as 1216.
1216  是的  先生
1216 -- that's correct, sir.
但在你們最初提交的文件中
But in the original submission,
寫的是羅塞拉路1261號
we're seeing 1261 Rosella Drive.
-是1261  -1261
- It is 1261. ‭- 1261.
如果你們復查一遍  就會發現應該是1216
I think if you double-check, you'll see that 1216 is correct.
似乎是兩個不同的地址
There seem to be ‭two different addresses here.
專員先生  我這兒有一份意向通知書復印件
Mr. Commissioner, I have a copy of our notice of intent,
之前發表在亞利桑那和新墨西哥州的報紙上
which was published in newspapers in Arizona and New Mexico.
上面明確寫著地址是羅塞拉路1261號
It clearly states the address is 1261 Rosella Drive.
專員先生...
Mr. -- ‭Mr. Commissioner, I-if --
羅塞拉路1261號
1-2-6-1 Rosella Drive.
是的  我這也有一份意向通知書
Yes, I have a copy of the notice of intent, too,
但是正式提交的文件上
but on the actual filing,
地址寫的是1216號
the address reads 1-2-1-6.
所以...哪個才對
So...which is it?
專員先生  我能與委托人交換意見嗎
Mr. Commissioner, ‭if I may confer with my clients?
沒問題  請
Certainly, please.
絕對是1261號
It's absolutely 1261.
你搞錯了
You are mistaken,
恕我直言  你這是在添亂
and with all due respect, you're muddying the waters here.
"添亂"
"Muddying the water"?
看
‭Look.
自己看
Just look.
這很明顯是個錯誤
Well, ‭this is clearly an error.
是1261沒錯
It's 1261.
我當然知道自己的銀行在哪
I know where my own damn bank is.
我們都冷靜一下
Uh, let's just all calm down.
肯定可以理清楚的
I'm sure we can straighten this out.
我在羅塞拉路1261號改造了一棟樓
I've got a building remodel at 1261 Rosella.
我倒不知道1216號是哪里
I don't know where the hell 1216 is.
我不太明白...  1261
I-I don't quite underst-- 1261.
-是1261  -這有什么問題嗎
- 1261. - ‭Is this gonna be a problem?
不會  肯定沒問題
No, I'm sure it won't be.
專員先生  抱歉
Um, M-Mr. Commissioner, I apologize.
不知為何  我們的文件里
Unaccountably, there appears to be a...
似乎出現了矛盾
discrepancy in our filing.
所以正確的地址
So the correct address the one
是意向通知書上的1261號嗎
that appeared in the notice of intent, the 1261?
看似如此
It would seem so.
我們想請求...
Uh, uh, uh, ‭we'd like to request a, um,
休會幾分鐘
an adjournment of just a few minutes
好讓我們將文件修改為正確的地址
so that we can amend the filing to reflect the correct address.
我可以允許休會
Well, I-I can give you an adjournment, uh, uh,
但是...
but, uh...uh,
今天可能沒辦法重新聽證了
I don't think we can get you back in today.
請問什么時候可以重新安排聽證
If I may, when do you think you might be able to schedule us?
工作人員告知
I'm being told by staff
他們已經對羅塞拉路1216號進行了調查
that they've already done the research for 1216 Rosella Drive.
如此一來我們的人又得去新的地址
Our folks are going to have to go back to square one
-從頭開始  -如果...
- on the new address. - If we --
如果我們今天能取得一份臨時協議
we could obtain a provisional agreement today,
允許分行設立...
to allow the -- the branch to open be--
不  不  恕我直言
No, no. All due respect,
提交準確的文件是你們的責任
it's up to you folks to submit accurate paperwork.
下次最好再次核對
Maybe next time, double-check.
如今  最快能夠重新聽證的時間
Now, uh, the soonest we could revisit this matter --
應該是六周后的周五
well, it -- it looks like six weeks from Friday.
我們等不了六個星期
We -- ‭We can't wait six weeks.
專員先生  梅薩維德銀行已耗費精力與資源
Mr. Commissioner, M-Mesa Verde has put effort and...resources
準備好即刻讓分行開張
into preparing this branch to open immediately.
雖然罕有先例  如果能給個臨時許可
However unusual, a provisional a-approval
我們會感激不盡
would be most appreciated, most welcome.
時間至關重要...
Time being of the essence --
查爾斯  很抱歉  我們六周后見
Charles, I'm sorry. I'll see you in six weeks.
今天就到此為止
That closes the matter for today.
工作人員請注明
Will staff please note
梅薩維德將于六周后返回
that Mesa Verde will return in six weeks...
屆時再重新對該申請聽證
...at which time, we will revisit this application?
已經安排好了
That's on the schedule now.
我們會加快進行所有新增調查
And we'll have expedited all the additional research.
不可能
This is not possible.
這不可能
This is not possible!
1261  不可能
1261. No. No.
查克
Chuck. ‭
我不懂
I don't understand.
我不懂  是1216號
I don't understand. It was 1216.
沒錯的  我檢查了一遍
It was. I checked!
又檢查一遍
I double-checked!
查克  發生就發生了
Chuck, it happened.
我們接受失敗  繼續前進
Now we take our licks, and we move on.
這不僅僅是你的錯
This doesn't just reflect on you --
律所里這么多律師和助理都疏忽了
an office full of associates and paralegals let this get by.
包括我自己
I did, too, for that matter.
是1216號  我保證
It was 1216 -- I promise you.
每個人都會犯錯
Everyone makes mistakes.
這不是犯錯
This was no mistake.
希臘甜品屋
我請這兒所有人喝一杯
I'm buying a round for the house.
-真的  -沒錯
- Yeah? - ‭Yeah.
大伙聽好
Hey, listen up, everybody!
這位先生要請所有人喝一杯
This gentleman's buyin a round for the house!
好了  用膝蓋的力
All right, lift with your knees
那到底什么意思  "用膝蓋的力"
What does that even mean -- "Lift with your knees"?
不知道  汗流浹背的人會說的話  來吧
I don't know. It's something sweaty people say. Here we go.
一  二  三
1, 2, 3.
-好了嗎  -差一點
- Got it. - Almost.
快了  快了  快了  快了
Almost, almost, almost, almost.
-好了嗎  -好了
- Got it? ‭- All right.
好了  就這兒  放手  放手
Oh, right there. Go. Go.
你還好吧
You okay?
做幾年的理療肯定能治好
Nothin a few years ‭of physical therapy won't fix.
-好  -好  推
- ‭Okay. - All right. Push.
慢點  慢點  慢點
Slow, slow, slow, slow.
轉角  轉角  轉角
Corner, corner, corner.
對  抓著那頭
Yeah. ‭Get that one.
你好  佩琪
Hi, Paige.
你還好嗎
How are you?
是  哦不
Yeah, I mean, no.
沒事的
No, it's fine.
什么
What?
可以啊
Well, yes.
當然可以  我理解
Of course. Right, I understand.
好的
Okay.
那真是太好了
Yeah, that would be perfect.
到時候再見  好的
I'll see you then. Great.
還有  佩琪  謝謝你
And, uh, listen, Paige, thank you.
謝謝
Thank you.
我
I, uh.
吉米
Jimmy.
什么  怎么了
What? What's up?
我
I, uh...
梅薩維德銀行回來了
I just got Mesa Verde back.
-真的嗎  -真的
- Seriously? ‭- Seriously.
-真棒  不敢置信  -就是啊
- Holy shit! That's unbelievable! - Yes.
我  那哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所怎么回事
I -- What happened to HHM?
佩琪沒細說
Uh, Paige didn't go into it.
她只說文件沒通過
She just said ‭the filing didn't go through.
我們今天下午見面
We're gonna meet this afternoon.
你看  我說吧
Hey, what did I tell you?
好人總有好報
Sometimes, the good guys win.
好像有些監管方面的問題
Oh, it sounds like ‭there's some regulatory issues.
凱文還是擔心一個律師不能勝任
Kevin's still worried that one lawyer won't be able to handle it.
你可以的
You can.
我得請個律師助理  也許要兩個
Yeah, I'm gonna have to get a paralegal, maybe two of them,
報酬肯定我一個人付
and I absolutely ‭will pay for it out of my end.
不  我倆平分報酬
No. Come on. Split it down the middle.
我得趕快弄個萬律數據庫終端
You know what? I need ‭a Westlaw terminal right away.
我都不知道這種事該打電話給誰
I don't even know who to call to get that done.
這都是高端的問題
These are high-class problems.
但這活兒可不小  吉米
Yeah, but it's a major piece of work, Jimmy.
很  很復雜
It's just -- It's -- It's -- This is major.
金  你可以的  好嗎
Hey, Kim, you've got this, all right?
先緩一下
So take a moment. ‭
深呼吸  享受勝利
Breathe. Savor.
你說得對
You know what? You're right.
我當然對
Damn right I'm right.
是歐尼
It's Ernie.
歐尼  什么事
Hi, Ernie. What's up?
是的  沒有  佩琪剛打電話給我
Yeah, no, Paige just called me.
查克說了為什么
Did Chuck say why --
那什么時候
So, when --
好的  現在去正好
Sure. ‭No time like the present.
好的  謝謝
Okay. Thanks.
梅薩維德的文件
The Mesa Verde files --
查克說可以給我了
Chuck's ready ‭to turn them to me.
真的
Really?
好快啊
That was... quick.
是啊
Yeah.
我換個衣服就過去
Uh, I'm gonna go change and get over there.
-需要幫忙嗎  -看情況
- You want some help? ‭- That depends.
你是幫著搬箱子  還是在旁邊幸災樂禍
Are you gonna carry boxes, or you gonna gloat?
兩個都要有一點吧
Uh, some from column "A," Some from column "B."
放個電
Ground yourself.
什么
W-- Sorry?
就碰一下那個東西
Just touch the thing.
怎么回事  開不開
What the hell? This thing doesn't...
-吉米你好  金你好  -歐尼你好
- Hey, Jimmy. Hey, Kim. - ‭Hey, Ernie.
鎖出了點問題
Somethin's wrong with the lock.
麥吉爾讓我打電話給鎖匠換掉了
Mr. McGill had me call a locksmith and changed them.
是嗎  為什么呢
Yeah? Why'd he do that?
查克  為什么要換鎖
Hey, Chuck, why'd you change the locks?
歐內斯托  我這里沒什么事了
Ernesto, I think we're good.
你肯定還要回辦公室吧
I'm sure you're needed back at the office.
那我走了
Well... I'll get going, then.
-謝謝  -再見  吉米  再見  金
- Thanks. - ‭Bye, Jimmy. Bye, Kim.
-歐尼  再見  -歐尼  回見
-Bye, Ernie. -See ya, Ernie.
那么  查克  鎖怎么了
So, Chuck, ‭what's the deal with the locks?
金  本來這些話我想對你說
Kim, I was hoping to have this conversation with you
對你一個人說
and you alone.
但是
However...
我想現在該澄清所有事實了
I guess it's time to clear the air once and for all.
澄清什么事實
Clear the air about what?
他陷害了我
He sabotaged me.
兄弟  你說什么
Buddy, what are you, uh...
拜托  省省吧
Please. Don't bother.
你我都知道我要說什么
You and I both know ‭exactly what I'm talking about.
我不知道
I don't.
昨天早上是我職業生涯中最大的羞辱
Yesterday morning was the worst professional humiliation of my life.
一個小小的字序問題  浪費了委托人的
A single transpositional error cost my client time and money
錢和時間  永遠破壞了我的名譽
and permanently damaged my reputation.
但我發現  不是錯誤
But then I realized... it wasn't an error.
根本不是
Not at all.
一周前的一晚  我就睡在沙發上
A week ago last night, I was right there on that couch,
幾乎失去了意識  吉米來了
barely consious, and Jimmy showed up.
支走了歐內斯托
and he sent Ernesto away.
我的好弟弟要親自照顧我
My brother was gonna take care of me.
在夜深之時
And in the dead of night,
他翻了我的梅薩維德的文件
he went through my Mesa Verde files.
我們不用聽你在這胡言亂語
Uh, you know what? We don't have to listen to this.
她得聽
She does!
好好聽  為你自己好
You do -- for your own good.
這里面有十三份文件
Now, in these files are 13 documents
標有梅薩維德銀行擬設支行的地址
containing the address of Mesa Verde's proposed branch --
羅塞拉路1261號  亞利桑那州斯科茨代爾
1261 Rosella Drive, Scottsdale, arizona.
吉米抽出每一份文件
Jimmy pulled each and every one,
留下我在這里大汗淋漓神志不清
then he left me here, sweating and delirious,
然后跑出去篡改了它們
while he went off to doctor them.
你需要復印機啊
You'd need a photocopier for that.
你去哪了  某個通宵營業的復印店嗎
Where'd you go -- some all-night copy shop?
經過小心剪切和粘貼后
With a little careful cutting and pasting,
他做好了復制品
he created duplicates --
跟原件幾乎一模一樣
virtually identical to my originals,
只有一處關鍵差別
but with one key change --
羅塞拉路1261號成了羅塞拉路1216號
1261 Rosella Drive ‭became 1216 Rosella Drive.
這聽起來可是大工程
This is sounding like a lot of work.
沒人說你懶
No one ever accused you of being lazy --
你有各種缺點  唯獨不懶
every other sin in the book, but not that one.
如果你想知道
And if you're wondering
吉米有沒有能力偽造文書
if Jimmy's up to a little casual forgery,
那我告訴你
you should know in high school,
他高中時就曾靠偽造身份證件日進斗金
he had a thriving business making fake I.Ds
讓他的兄弟們都有啤酒喝
so his buddies could buy beer.
高中的事你也提嗎
You going all the way back to high school, huh?
你跟莫扎特一樣
Hey, you and Mozart, huh?
都是從小就有天分
You both started young.
他回來之后  便把復制品夾在我的文件里
He came back here and put his new versions in my files.
然后  第二天
And then, the next day,
我那體貼的弟弟就離開了
my caring brother took his leave.
他知道我會用他篡改過的文件
He knew that I would use his modified documents
撰寫梅薩維德銀行的申請報告
to write Mesa Verde's submission to the state regulator.
也確實如此  我一遍遍地
And so I did, over and over --
輸入著1216  而不是1261
I typed "1216" instead of "1261."
我當時還想  "羅塞拉路1216
I remember thinking, "1216 Rosella Drive --
"是1215年的下一年
"that's just one year after 1215,
"是《大憲章》簽署的第二年"
"the year the Magna Carta was signed."
天哪  查克  你瘋了吧
Jesus, Chuck, you are unbelievable.
所以你的意思是  里面這些文件
So, you're saying, if we look in here,
上面的地址都是錯誤的
all the addresses will be wrong?
你當然不會留下證據
Well, of course you weren't gonna leave evidence behind.
我猜昨天早上  你等到我走了之后
I'm guessing yesterday morning, you waited until I left,
用你的鑰匙進了門
then used your key to let yourself in
把原始文件還了回來
and return the originals.
沒有掩蓋的犯罪是不完整的
No crime is complete without the cover-up.
天哪拜托
Oh, come on.
我為什么要這么做  為了什么生意嗎
I did all this -- what -- for some business?
他都是為了你
He did it for you.
你對此肯定一點都不知情
Oh, I'm sure you didn't know anything about it.
這肯定是他自己的主意
I believe he went off on his own
把這當成某種扭曲的浪漫之舉
and did this as some kind of twisted romantic gesture.
查克  你應該躺下來
Chuck, ‭I think you need to lie down
用冷毛巾敷敷額頭了
with a cold washcloth on your head.
現在你知道了  你別無選擇了
And now that you know, you have no choice.
這事關委托人  一個被欺騙的委托人
This is about a client -- a client who has been defrauded.
作為一名宣過誓的律師
As a sworn officer of the court,
作為梅薩維德銀行的正式代理律師
as Mesa Verde's attorney of record,
你只能去找凱文·沃弛泰爾
you have no recourse but to go to Kevin Wachtell
把這一切和盤托出
and make a full disclosure.
他這一整套說辭
This -- This whole song and dance --
只是為了奪回他的委托人
it's all about getting his client back.
-就是為了這個目的  -完全不是
- That's all this is. - ‭Not in the least.
如果他們得知真相后仍然決定...
If, knowing the truth, they still decide to go --
你不能忍受他們選擇了她而不是你
You can't stand the fact that they chose her over you.
我不能忍受的是
I can't stand the fact
我的親弟弟在我背后捅刀子
that my own brother stabbed me in the back!
我不能忍受你欺騙了這位年輕的女士
I can't stand the fact that you've deceived
-讓她墮落至此  -"墮落"
- and ruined this fine young woman! - ‭"Ruined"?
現在是十九世紀四十年代嗎
What is this -- the 1840s?
你說什么呢  她才沒有墮落
What are you talking about? She's not ruined!
吉米
Jimmy.
如果你說的都是真的
If what you're saying is true,
吉米會被指控偽造文書  詐騙
Jimmy could be charged with forgery, fraud,
偽造證據  甚至非法侵入
falsifying evidence, even breaking and entering.
坦白說  我也很難受
Frankly, I am sick about this.
但事實就是事實
But facts are facts.
你有證據嗎
And what is your evidence?
證據
My evidence?
證據就是我十分了解我的弟弟
My evidence is knowing my brother for his entire life.
查克  還有別的解釋
Chuck, I think ‭there is another explanation --
一個更簡單的解釋
it's a simpler one.
你看錯了
You made a mistake.
我沒有
I did not.
你在油燈下工作
You're wororking by lantern,
瞇著眼盯著那些打印出來的十磅小字
squinting over 10-point type for hour after hour.
錯把1261當成了1216
Mistakenly changing 1261 to 1216
這是極其正常的事情
would be the most natural thing in the world.
我也可能犯這樣的錯
It could certainly happen to me.
我沒有搞錯
I did not make a mistake!
就是你搞錯了
I believe you did.
我知道  你很喜歡吉米
Look, I understand that you have a -- a great affection for Jimmy.
很多人都喜歡  但請你睜開眼睛
A great many people do, but please open your eyes here!
你犯了一個錯誤  你非但不去面對它
You made a mistake, and instead of just facing up to it,
反而指責你的弟弟陷害你
you accuse your brother of plotting against you.
編造出這么精心策劃的陰謀
You come up ‭with this elaborate scheme.
他做得出來
He's capable of this!
我知道他能
You know he is!
我知道他有很多缺點
I know he's not perfect!
我知道他喜歡走捷徑
And I know he cuts corners.
但是你讓他變成這樣的
But you're the one who made him this way.
他崇拜你
He idolizes you.
他接受你
He accepts you.
他照顧你
He takes care of you.
他只想要你的愛與支持
And all he ever wanted was your love and support,
但你只會對他指手畫腳
but all you've ever done is judge him.
你從來不相信他
You never believed in him.
你從來不希望他成功
You never wanted him to succeed.
你知道嗎
And you know what?
我為他感到難過
I feel sorry for him.
也為你感到難過
And I feel sorry for you.
天啊  干什么
Jesus! What? ‭
金  干什么
Kim! What?
給我  開車
Just drive.
好了  根據班級排好隊
All right, line up by class!
去找你們的小伙伴
Find your buddy!
孩子們  過來
Okay, kids, come on.
我們上
Let's go.
來  來
Come on. Come on.
-趕緊各就各位  -這邊嗎
- Plant yourself. ‭- All right. Here?
沒錯  這邊
Yeah. Right there.
這么高就行了
About yea high. ‭
對準我  拍出英雄氣概
Aim it up at me -- heroic.
英雄氣概  祝你好運了
Heroic? Good luck with that.
趕緊給我拍
Just frame me up, all right?
把脖子也給化好
Make sure you get the neck, okay?
-這是從下方拍攝的  -好的
- It's a low-angle shoot. ‭- Okay.
算了  讓我看看
Hey, you know what? Let me see.
這只是打個底
Oh, I-it's just base.
我這是得肺癆要死了嗎
What -- am I dying of consumption?
你這個年齡段的人沒那么紅潤
Well, at your age, ‭you don't want to look too red.
-應該有點紅斑痤瘡  -那這些...
- It looks like rosacea. - And what's with all the...
我只是想化出你下巴的輪廓
I'm just trying to make it look like you have a jawline.
我下巴本來就有輪廓
I do have a jawline.
這樣吧  你站過去
You know what? You stand in for me.
蹲一點
Hey, crouch down.
往左  另一邊
Okay. Move to your left. The other left.
再左一點  好了
More. More. Okay, boom!
我就是這個意思  懂了吧
That's what I'm talkinin about. You got it.
肯定還有更簡單的拍攝方式
Oh, dude, there's got to be an easier way to get this shot.
免費的可沒有
Not for free.
你要想拍電影  就得膽子大
You wanna be a filmmaker, grow a pair.
好了  準備正式拍攝
Here we go. Picture's up.
好  我們開始吧
All right, let's do this.
最后補一下
Last looks.
大黃  大黃  九點鐘方向
Rhubarb, Rhubarb. 9:00.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你是這里的負責人嗎
Hi. Are you in charge here?
是的  這是學校用地
Yes, I am, ‭and this is school property.
我正要找你呢
You're just the person I want to speak to.
如果你能讓那幢樓里的孩子小聲點
It would be incredibly helpful if you could get those kids in that building
會對我們很有幫助的
over there to just keep it down for a bit.
讓他們做點練習之類的
Just give 'em a worksheet or something?
只要兩三分鐘  很快的
I mean, just two or three minutes, just for sound.
這里是學校用地
This is school property,
未經允許任何人都不得入內
and no one is allowed here without permission.
當然了
Of course not.
-安奈特沒和你說嗎  -安奈特是誰
- You didn't speak to Annette? - ‭Annette?
主管辦公室的
In the Superintendent's office.
你認識城里叫安奈特的嗎
Do you know an Annette downtown?
不認識
I don't think so.
抱歉添麻煩了
Well, I'm sorry about the mix-up.
我們在拍"定場鏡頭"...
We're shooting what's called an establishing shot --
最多五分鐘
five minutes, tops.
我弄清楚之前
You're not shooting anything
你們什么都不準拍
until I'm clear on what's going on here.
紀錄片  我們在拍紀錄片
The documentary -- we're making a documentary.
是...
That's -- Oh!
我聽說有個展覽或者紀念牌匾之類的
I was told there was a display or a plaque of some kind.
你知道在哪里嗎
Would you know where that would be?
我們為什么會有牌匾
Why would we have a plaque?
因為曾在這里上過學的人
Because of who went to school here.
誰曾在這里上過學
Who went to school here?
魯伯特·霍姆斯
Rupert Holmes.
就是關于他的紀錄片
That's who the documentary is about.
抱歉  誰
I'm sorry. Who?
魯伯特·霍姆斯
Rupert Holmes.
魯伯特·霍姆斯  創作歌手
You know...Rupert Holmes, the singer/songwriter.
"椰林飄香之歌"
You know, um... "The Piña Colada Song."
一種雞尾酒
你肯定知道  我...
I mean, sure you do. I...
*如果你喜歡椰林飄香  被大雨困住*
*If you like piña coladas and getting caught in the rain*
*如果你不喜歡瑜伽  還算有點腦子*
*If you're not into yoga and you got half a brain*
*如果你喜歡半夜啪啪啪*
*If you like makin' love at midnight*
*在海角旁的沙丘*
*In the dunes by the cape...*
知道嗎  魯...  看看她的臉
See? Ru-- Look at her face.
-魯伯特·霍姆斯  -他在這上過學嗎
- Rupert Holmes. - ‭He went to school here?
是啊  64屆的
Yeah. Class of '64.
他現在還經常說
He still talks about it.
但這所學校是71年建的
But the school was built in '71.
他在那之前的老樓里上過學
Mm. He was a student in the old building that used to be here.
我們有點...怎么說呢
We're taking a little -- what do you call it?
藝術再創作
Artistic liberties.
魯伯特·霍姆斯不是英國人嗎
Isn't Rupert Holmes English?
是啊  這可以拿來做小趣事
Well, yeah, ‭and that's some great trivia,
但他青少年時期是在阿爾布開克度過的
but he spent his formative years right here in Albuquerque.
這樣吧  你打到主管辦公室
I'll tell you what -- why don't you call Annette
找安奈特
down in ‭the Superintendent's Office?
我們就在這等官方回話
And we'll just stay here till you get official word.
-好  如果你不介意等的話  -不會
- Well, ‭if you don't mind waiting. - Not at all.
我們不想違反任何規定
We don't want to break any rules.
不會太久的
Shouldn't take very long, I'm sure.
雖然不能保證
And no promises,
但我盡量讓孩子們安靜點
but I'll see what I can do about getting the kids to quiet down.
那真是幫了大忙了
Oh. ‭That would be super helpful.
快點  這時候正好
Chop-chop. Magic time.
-快點  -好的
- Come on, let's go. - All right
不做造型了  把旗子降下來
No last looks. ‭Just the flag -- the flag.
好  記著  英雄氣概
Okay, remember -- heroic.
好  你是個英雄
Yeah, you're a hero.
-大英雄  -要莊重
- Big, big hero. - ‭Gravitas.
開始
Go.
推  推  推
Dolly, dolly, dolly.
漂亮
Nice.
-你好  麥克  -你好  弗蘭
- Hey, Mike. ‭- Hey, Fran.
還供應早餐嗎
You still serving breakfast?
你來就供應  老樣子嗎
For you? Sure. The usual?
好的
Um, be great.
謝謝
Thanks.
有什么好事嗎
Anything good in the paper?
沒有
No.
報紙上有過好事嗎
Was there ever anything good in the paper?
確實不多
Not too often.
-弗蘭  -怎么
- Hey, Fran. - ‭Yeah?
我問一下
I got to ask...
這里下過雪嗎
does it ever snow around here?
下過
Sure, it does.
你要在阿爾布開克度過第一個冬天嗎
This is gonna be your first winter in Albuquerque?
沒錯  我從費城來
Yeah. I'm out from Philadelphia.
看哪一年吧
Well, it depends on the year.
如果你待得夠久
If you stay around long enough,
就會有雪鏟的  不用擔心
you'll have something to shovel -- don't you worry.
我喜歡鏟雪
That suits me.
我住在錫達克雷斯特  經常下雪
I live up in Cedar Crest. We get plenty.
如果嫌不夠可以來鏟我家車道的雪
You can shovel my drive if you're looking for more.
一句話的事
Just say the word.
好吧
Yeah, well...
小姐  結賬
Miss. check, please?
喂
Yeah.
我們得談談
We gotta talk.
我得知道些事
I've got something I need to know,
立刻告訴我
and I need to know it fast.
什么事
What's that?
我們不久前被搶了
We got hit the other day.
一輛向南開的卡車被劫了
A truck headed south got hijacked.
有人偷了二十五萬
Someone stole a quarter million.
現在赫克托氣瘋了  在找是誰干的
Now Hector's flippin' out, lookin' for who did it.
問題是
Thing is...
我覺得是你
I think it was you.
司機被綁起來了  身上卻沒有傷痕
They left the driver hog-tied -- not a mark on him.
干這一行的都殺人不眨眼
Anyone in the game would capped him without a second thought.
但這個司機還活著
But this driver? He's still breathin'.
我就琢磨  這家伙是誰
I thought to myself, "who's the guy
搶了幾十萬毒資
who'll rip off a couple hundred thousand
還留一個目擊者
in drug money and leave a witness?
什么人不愿開槍
Who's the guy ‭who won't pull the trigger?"
就是你
You.
我不是來勒索你的
I'm not here to squeeze you.
你想搶販毒集團  那是你的事
You wanna rip off the cartel, that's your business.
但問題是
But here's the thing.
我要去接那個司機  赫克托的命令
I'm picking up that driver -- Hector's orders.
我們要看看他知道什么
We're gonna see what he knows,
如果他認識你  那對我倆都不好
and if he knows you, that's bad for both of us.
你不用擔心
That shouldn't concern you.
但他跟你是一伙的  對吧
But he was in on it, right?
那司機和此事無關
The driver ‭had nothing to do with it.
-那是誰  -只有我
- Then who? - ‭Just me.
你是說你干這票  里頭沒人嗎
You're telling me you did this without someone on the inside?
不可能
Not possible.
你怎么知道那輛卡車的
How did you know about the truck?
你怎么知道在輪胎里
How do you know about the tires?
要我說
All I can tell you is,
你們高估了自己的智商
you guys aren't half as smart as you think you are.
所以那個司機什么都不知道嗎
So the driver... doesn't know anything?
-什么都不知道  -他聽到你聲音了嗎
- Not a thing. - ‭He hear your voice?
-沒有  -現在赫克托還在查競爭對手
- No. - ‭Right now, Hector's looking at the competition,
但他要是聽司機說是個年紀大的美國佬...
but he hears the driver say it was some old gringo...
他沒聽到我說話
He didn't hear me.
他就看到一個戴滑雪面具的人而已
He saw a guy with a ski mask -- that's it.
你肯定
And you're sure of that?
沒錯
Yeah.
你最好別搞錯
You better be right.
為什么沒上報紙
Why wasn't it in the papers?
什么
What?
卡車劫案  警察沒讓上報紙嗎
The truck robbery -- the cops keeping it out of the papers?
警察
The cops?
警察什么都不知道
The cops don't know shit about it.
怎么會呢
How's that?
這就是你的目的嗎
Is that what this is about?
你想讓警察去抓赫克托
You wanted to put the cops onto Hector?
為什么
Why?
你對他不重要
You are nothing to him.
他完全忘了你
He forgot all about you.
我可沒忘記他
I haven't forgotten him.
你把我推進火坑
You put me in the shit,
就因為你想整赫克托·塞拉曼加
just 'cause you got it in for Hector Salamanca?
你把警察引向了他  也就引向了我
Listen, you put the cops on him, you put them on me.
你要是為了錢  我懂  但你這樣
Doing it for the money -- I get it, but this shit --
真是瘋了
that's insane.
你得冷靜
You need to calm yourself down,
把手從那個口袋拿出來
and you need to take that hand out of that pocket.
你要明白
Now, just so you know...
都結束了
it's over.
我跟你老板的事結束了
I'm done with your boss.
算了
Whatever.
為什么沒上報紙
Why wasn't it in the papers?
因為我們收拾干凈了
Because we cleaned it up.
怎么收拾的
How's that?
我們很幸運
We got lucky.
你離開后  有個好心人過來
After you left, ‭a Good Samaritan came along
大叫"天啊  天啊"
and said, "Oh, my God! Oh, my God!"
他給司機松綁  司機叫我們過去
He cut the driver loose. The driver called us.
我們過去開走了卡車
We came out, got the truck.
就好像沒發生過一樣
Made it like it never happened.
那好心人呢
And that Good Samaritan?
赫克托崩了他的臉
Hector shot him in the face.
我們把他埋在了沙漠里
We buried the guy out in the desert.
我說了...
Like I said...
我們收拾干凈了
we cleaned it up.
你今天怎么樣
How was your day?
跟佩奇和凱文見面
You know, met with Paige and Kevin,
面試了些律師助理
interviewed some paralegals...
還有這個
and, uh, this.
你呢
What about you? ‭
拍完了廣告
Finished the commercial.
我不是賣弄  但這可能是
I don't want to oversell it, but I think it might be
電視史上最棒的六十秒
the greatest 60 seconds in the history of television.
明早
Tomorrow morning, uh,
11點18分到11點35分之間
somewhere between 11:18 and 11:35,
放下手中的活  轉到《謀殺診斷》
stop what you're doing and tune in to "Diagnosis Murder."
我記下來
I'll make a point of it.
你想談談這事嗎
You want to talk about this?
現在不
Not now.
以后也不
Not ever.
我只想說...
I'm just gonna say...
你和梅薩維德絕對應該合作
you are meant for Mesa Verde, and they are meant for you.
現在...一切都好了
So... all is right with the world.
晚安
Good night.
Night.
你哥是個聰明的律師
Your brother is one smart lawyer.
我認識的最聰明的  無意冒犯
The smartest one I know -- I mean, no offense.
他會是強勁的對手
He'd make quite an adversary.
你說得沒錯
You'd better believe it.
他是那種
The kind of adversary
會發現你辯詞中最細微漏洞的對手
who'd find even the smallest crack in your defense.
和他對抗  你真得確保
Going against him, you'd really want to make sure
你做得滴水不漏
you've got all your I's dotted and your T's crossed.
不留痕跡
Nothing for him to find.
二十四小時營業
你好嗎
Hey, how ya doin'?
一會兒就來
Be with you in a minute.
記得我嗎
Remember me?
不記得
Uh...no.
我覺得你應該記得  蘭斯
I got a weird feeling you do, Lance.
今晚很有趣
Tonight is a funny night.
不知什么原因
For some reason tonight,
我感覺自己獲得了全部答案
I feel like I've got all the answers...
感覺就好像
I'm feeling kind of like, uh...
約翰尼·卡爾森在《約翰尼·卡爾森今夜秀》中出演的角色
卡納克一樣
like Carnac.
你記得約翰尼·卡爾森過去演卡納克嗎
Do you remember when Johnny Carson used to do Carnac?
他會在問題提出前給出答案
You know, he'd give the answers before the questions.
埃德會給他信封  是吧
You know, Ed would give him the envelope, yeah?
約翰尼會將它頂住前額
And Johnny would hold it up to his forehead,
然后給出答案  比如
and, um, he'd give the answer, like,
上世紀五六十年代美國電視劇
"留給河貍"
"Leave It to Beaver."
然后約翰尼會打開信封
Then Johnny'd tear open the envelope.
問題是
And there's the question --
"浣熊的遺囑里寫了什么"
"What did the dead raccoon say in his will?"
想起來了嗎
That ring a bell?
你沒看過嗎
Before your time?
我們言歸正傳
All right, well, let's cut to the chase.
剛走出這里的男人
Um, that guy ‭who just walked out of here --
名叫歐尼
his name is Ernie.
他給你看了我的照片吧
I'm guessing he showed you my picture
還問你我那晚來過這沒有
and asked if ‭I was in here the other night.
他現在會帶他老板來  也就是我哥哥
Now he's going to bring his boss, who's my brother,
他會問你同樣的問題
and he's gonna ask you the same question --
"你那晚見過那人嗎"
"Did you see that guy the other night?"
答案是沒有
Well, the answer is no.
懂了嗎
You feel me?
你殺人了嗎
You murder someone?
沒有
Nope.
搶銀行了
Rob a bank?
我沒那么厲害
No way am I that cool.
我有時候上大號不沖廁所  但...
I -- sometimes, I go number two and I don't flush, but...
這是兄弟間的事
this is just a thing between brothers.
而且我們都是律師  所以...
And we're both lawyers, so...
那是個冗長又無聊的故事
Right? I mean, ‭that's a long and boring story.
你沒興趣的
You don't wanna know.
這件事會惹來警察嗎
Is this gonna get me jammed up with the cops?
我哥哥也許會跟你這么說  但是不會
My brotherer may make it sound like that, but...no.
家事而已
It's just family.
那我明白了
Then I feel you.
跟我說說攝像頭怎么回事
Hey, ‭tell me about the cameras.
后面有臺錄像機
Oh. Uh, they go to a VCR in the back.
每錄十二小時就回過頭重錄一遍
It, uh, tapes for 12 hours and then records over itself.
所以我現在被錄上嗎
Right. So I'm on there now?
要抹掉記錄有多困難
How hard would it be to erase?
我不確定
Mm. I don't know.
可能很麻煩...
Could be tricky...
而且很貴
and expensive.
像一百塊那么貴
Like 100 bucks expensive?
兩百塊那么貴
Like 200 bucks expensive.
你以后會大有作為的  年輕人
You will go far, my young friend.
晚上好
Uh, good evening.
蘭斯  對吧
Uh, Lance, is it?
對
Yeah.
蘭斯  我是查爾斯·麥吉爾
Lance, I'm Charles McGill.
我的助理之前找你談過
Uh, my associate, uh, spoke with you earlier,
他給你看了這張照片
and he showed you this photo.
大約在十八號凌晨的時候
Um, on or about ‭the morning of the 18th,
這個人來過這里
this person was here in this shop --
對嗎
is that correct?
大約在...
Uh. On or about the...
十八號  凌晨時分
The 18th, early morning.
沒有
No.
你告訴我的助手
Well, I'm -- ‭I believe you told my associate
他來過這里  還復印了文件
that he was here and that he made copies.
是的  抱歉
Yeah, but sorry.
沒來過
No.
好樣的  這就對了
Yeah, that's my guy.
好吧  星期二  十七號的晚上
All right, the, uh, th-the night of Tuesday the 17th --
到星期三凌晨
leading into early Wednesday,
也就是十八號星期三凌晨
early hours ‭of Wednesday the 18th...
你當時在這里嗎  這點能確定嗎
...were you, in fact, here? Can we establish that?
我是上夜班的
Uh, I mean, ‭I work graveyard,
所以  是的
so, yeah.
堅持住  蘭斯
Stay strong, Lance.
這個人來印過東西嗎
Was this man here, making copies?
我剛說了沒有
It's like I said -- I don't think so.
之前你說他來過
Well, earlier, ‭you said that he was here.
現在又說他沒來過
Now you're saying that he wasn't here.
哪個才是真話
Which is it?
那個人給我看照片的時候
Yeah, well, when that guy showed me the picture,
我想  "也許吧"  可現在我再仔細一看
I thought, "Maybe," But now that I'm seeing it again, uh...
抱歉
Ah, sorry.
怎么說呢
Don't know what to tell you.
看來我看錯了
Guess I was wrong.
孩子  仔細聽著
Son, ‭listen carefully.
我是一名法庭工作人員  在調查一起重案
I am an officer of the court, investigating a felony.
這么說你是警察
So you're a cop?
不  我不是  我...  我...
N-No, I'm not. ‭I'm -- I'm -- I'm, uh, I'm --
麥吉爾先生  也許該送您回家了
Mr. McGill, ‭maybe we better get you home.
歐內斯托  別把我當小孩
Ernesto, do not speak to me as if I were a child.
我沒事
I'm fine.
我不是警察
I am not a police officer.
我是一名律師
I am an attorney.
我在道義和法律上有責任
And I have a moral and legal obligation
把此事調查清楚
to get to the bottom of this matter.
調查清楚什么
The bottom of what?
偽造  欺詐  篡改證據
Forgery, fraud, falsifying evidence...
非法入侵
...breaking and entering.
這個人...他沒事吧
This guy -- is he okay?
我正常得很
There's nothing wrong with me!
麥吉爾先生  也許我們可以
Mr. McGill, maybe we could
-休息一下  然后  -厄尼  閉嘴
- just take a break and -- - Ernie, shut up!
你仔細考慮自己說的話
You think about ‭the choice you're making.
我跟你說了他沒來過
I already told you he wasn't here.
你還想讓我說什么
What do you want me to say?
我想讓你說出真相
I want you to speak the truth.
我知道他來過
I know he was here!
我知道他都干了什么
I know what he did!
把你和歐內斯托說的跟我說一遍
Tell me what you told Ernesto.
別再改變說辭了
Stop trying to change your story.
打擾一下  怎樣改成11x14的
Excuse me. Sorry. How do we get this to do 11x14?
不好意思
No, excuse me!
我們正在說話呢
We are having a conversation here!
你得切換到第四托盤
You got to switch it to tray four.
我給你演示會更直觀些  聽著
It's easier if I show you. Look.
老兄  好了
Dude, okay.
我不想惹麻煩
I-I -- I-I don't want any problems here.
你就...把他帶走吧
So, just... get him out of here,
不然我要報警了  好嗎
or I'm gonna call the cops, okay?
別走  我們還沒說完呢
Do not walk away from me! We are not finished here!
我已經和你說夠了  老兄
I am done talking to you, man!
快報警
Call 911.
快報警  拜托
Call 911. Come on.
各大應用市場均可下載
人人美劇APP看美劇就來人人美劇
更新快 無刪減
最大最全的美劇平臺
掃碼即刻下載